Guide to the Leslie Dorsey Collection of Pictorial Clippings 1860-1970 (bulk, 1860-1920) PR 17
New-York Historical Society
Leslie Dorsey collection of pictorial clippings
1860-1970 (bulk,1860-1920)
New-York Historical Society
Dorsey, Leslie
PR 17
87.83 Linear feet (69 boxes)
This collection contains the image library amassed by designer Leslie Dorsey, consisting primarily of images from or depicting the Victorian era.
Access restrictions
Materials in this collection may be stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Bequest of Leslie Dorsey, 1979.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged by subject in five series:
Series I. Clippings and wood engravings
Series II. Creative projects and research files
Series III. Scrapbooks
Series IV. Collages and graphics
Series V. Indexes and professional work
Some of the subject tiles reflect Dorsey's original arrangement and others were added to facilitate access to the materials.
Biographical note
Leslie Dorsey (1912-1979) started his career as a display manager for a specialty shop in Philadelphia. Sometime after 1940, he moved to New York City, where he designed displays for Richard Hudnut cosmetic products. He also designed hotel and restaurant interiors, and wrote, with Janice Devine, a whimsical history of American hotels entitled Fare Thee Well: A Backward Look at Two Centuries of Historic American Hostelries, Fashionable Spas and Seaside Resorts (New York: Crown Publisher, 1964).
A Victorian-era enthusiast, Dorsey also collected pictorial images from Godey's magazines and other period books and catalogs, and assembled them into scrapbooks for reference use in his interior design work. He also used these images to prepare collages which he marketed as "Decou-Optiques" to clients for use in advertisements or background murals. Eventually, Dorsey made his extensive image collection available for "rental" to commercial clients, effectively serving as an early stock image library.
Scope and Contents
The Leslie Dorsey Collection of Pictorial Clippings spans the period from 1850 to 1970 and consists primarily of images from Dorsey's extensive research library of engravings, magazine and catalog illustrations, chromos, and other printed ephemera and illustrations from the Victorian period. Also included are examples of Dorsey's various creative endeavors, including a book proposal, concept scrapbooks for two theatrical musicals, and a number of collages.
The collection has been organized into five series. Series I, Clippings and wood engravings, includes images that Dorsey cut out of period magazines and catalogs and arranged by topic in three ring binders. The binders have been disbound and the contents housed in acid-free folders. Topics are listed alphabetically in the box and folder list, and include, among many others, Agricultural Implements and Farming, Animals, Children, Drugs and Druggists, and Interior Decorations. There are also multiple folders relating to fashion, arranged by date.
Series II, Creative Projects and Research Files, includes Dorsey's proposal for a book on the Centennial Exhibition as well as "concept" sketchbooks containing proposals for two theatrical musicals ("The Ballad of Josie and Jim," about the murder of robber baron Jim Fiske over actress Josie Mansfield, and "Centennial Quartette," a celebration of the 1876 Centennial Exhibition in Philadelphia). The scrapbooks have been disbound and housed in acid-free folders. This series also includes some of Dorsey's research files, consisting of contemporaneous newspaper and magazine articles on the Bicentennial of 1976 and a few other topics (Antiques, Art Nouveau, the Metropolitan Opera House and Restaurants and Food). In addition, there are a few folders of ephemera, primarily relating to architectural preservation and tourism in New York City.
Series III, Scrapbooks, includes images and other materials that Dorsey assembled into scrapbooks to illustrate various topics. Topics include dining, drinking, hotels, Christmas, sports, and fairs and expositions (Crystal Palace, Centennial, Columbian, Louisiana Purchase, and Pan-American). There are also a number of scrapbooks relating to New York City, covering a broad range of topics such as Equestrian, 23rd Street, Courthouses and Criminals, and New York City Markets. Additional topics are identified in the box and folder list.
Series IV, Collages and graphics, includes examples of Dorsey's "Decou-Optiques," or collages, which he apparently marketed to clients for use in advertisements or as background murals for articles or products. This series includes both black and white and color collages, depicting various period and historical scenes, including many Christmas scenes. Also included are examples of some of the materials Dorsey used to create the collages, such as decals and cut-out figures.
Dorsey indexed some of his scrapbooks, and these can be found in Series V, Indexes and business papers. Also included in this series are articles and press releases relating to Dorsey, examples of advertisements and articles from Dorsey's clients that incorporate his images, and photographic portraits of Dorsey.
- Series I. Clippings and wood engravings
  Scope and Contents
  This series consists primarily of advertisements and images from Victorian-era publications. Dorsey cut the images out, pasted them onto notebook paper, and arranged them into three-ring binders by topic. The binders have been disbound and the material housed in acid-free folders.
  The illustrations in the series cover a broad range of topics, from fashion (the largest single category) to fire-fighting equipment. Many of the topics relate to household and interior design, for example, cases and boxes, silver and cutlery, garden statuary, lighting, house design, etc. There are also a number of pictorial vignettes and genre scenes of children, courtship and romance, and outdoor recreation. Animals and plants are also well-represented.
  Although most of the images arranged by subject are wood engravings, there is also a separate category of "wood engravings" at the end of the series, which was originally housed in three binders. Dorsey prepared a subject index for these binders (included in Box 11, Folder 1), which lists the following topics: artists, automobiles, balloons, bicycles, buildings, children, Christmas, circus, clocks and watches, design devices, drinking, entertainment, flowers, food and dining, general store, home furnishing, horses and wagons, hotels, houses, medicine, men, music, office furnishings, optical, patriotic and symbols, perfume, photography, rope, rural, ships, sports, stores, telegram, toys, trains, trolley, weather, the west, winter, and women.
  - Agricultural Implements and Farming; Slaughtering hogs (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
  - Animals (domestic and wild) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
  - Art Galleries; Engraving; Photography (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Awnings & tents; bricks and lanes; irons and ironworks (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Birds, Insects, and Fish (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Cases and boxes; silver and cutlery (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - Children (pages 1-90) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
  - Children (pages 91-186) (Offsite-box 1, Folder 8)
  - Children (Offsite-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Clothing stores and merchants (Offsite-box 2, Folder 1)
  - Courtship and romance; Outdoor recreation (Offsite-box 2, Folder 2)
  - Drugs and druggists (includes dietary aids); medicine and doctors; optical (Offsite-box 2, Folder 3)
  - Fashion 1866-1867 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 4)
  - Fashion, 1873 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fashion, 1874-1875 (Offsite-box 2, Folder 6)
  - Fashion, 1876 (folder 1 of 3) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 7)
  - Fashion, 1876 (folder 2 of 3) (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
  - Fashion, 1876 (folder 3 of 3) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 1)
  - Fashion, 1877 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 2)
  - Fashion, 1878 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 3)
  - Fashion, 1880 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 4)
  - Fashion, 1881 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 5)
  - Fashion, 1892 (folder 1 of 2) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 6)
  - Fashion, 1892 (folder 2 of 2) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 7)
  - Fashion, 1894 (folder 1 of 3) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 8)
  - Fashion, 1894 (folder 2 of 3) (Offsite-box 4, Folder 1)
  - Fashion, 1894 (folder 3 of 3) (Offsite-box 4, Folder 2)
  - Fashion, 1895 (folder 1 of 3) (Offsite-box 4, Folder 3)
  - Fashion, 1895 (folder 2 of 3) (Offsite-box 4, Folder 4)
  - Fashion, 1895 (folder 3 of 3) (Offsite-box 4, Folder 5)
  - Fashion, 1896 (folder 1 of 3) (Offsite-box 4, Folder 6)
  - Fashion, 1896 (folder 2 of 3) (Offsite-box 4, Folder 7)
  - Fashion, 1896 (folder 3 of 3) (Offsite-box 5, Folder 1)
  - Fashion, 1897 (folder 1 of 4) (Offsite-box 5, Folder 2)
  - Fashion, 1897 (folder 2 of 4) (Offsite-box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fashion, 1897 (folder 3 of 4) (Offsite-box 5, Folder 4)
  - Fashion, 1897 (folder 4 of 4) (Offsite-box 5, Folder 5)
  - Fashion, 1898 (folder 1 of 4) (Offsite-box 5, Folder 6)
  - Fashion, 1898 (folder 2 of 4) (Offsite-box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fashion, 1898 (folder 3 of 4) (Offsite-box 6, Folder 1)
  - Fashion, 1898 (folder 4 of 4) (Offsite-box 6, Folder 2)
  - Fashion, 1899 (folder 1 of 3) (Offsite-box 6, Folder 3)
  - Fashion, 1899 (folder 2 of 3) (Offsite-box 6, Folder 4)
  - Fashion, 1899 (folder 3 of 3) (Offsite-box 6, Folder 5)
  - Fashion, 1900 (Offsite-box 6, Folder 6)
  - Men and fashion (Offsite-box 6, Folder 7)
  - Women and fashion (Offsite-box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fashion, Strawbridge and Clothier Catalogs 1904, 1907-1910, 1912 (Offsite-box 7, Folder 1)
  - Firearms and hunting; Fireworks; Billiards (Offsite-box 7, Folder 2)
  - Fire-fighting equipment; Police and crime prevention equipment (Offsite-box 7, Folder 3)
  - Fire-places, Stoves and Heating (Offsite-box 7, Folder 4)
  - Foundries; Iron and Steel Works; Machinery (Offsite-box 7, Folder 5)
  - Furniture; door hardware (Offsite-box 7, Folder 6)
  - Garden statuary, furniture and implements (Offsite-box 7, Folder 7)
  - Glass bottles and vases (Offsite-box 7, Folder 8)
  - Horses & Carriages; Sleighs (Offsite-box 7, Folder 9)
  - House design (Offsite-box 7, Folder 10)
  - Interior decorations; Architectural ornaments (Offsite-box 8, Folder 1)
  - Jewelry; Corsets; and Undergarments (Offsite-box 8, Folder 2)
  - Kitchen and household; Ice and refrigeration (Offsite-box 8, Folder 3)
  - Lighting (Offsite-box 8, Folder 4)
  - Logging and lumber; Mining (Offsite-box 8, Folder 5)
  - Needlework (embroidery, etc); Sewing; Scissors (Offsite-box 8, Folder 6)
  - New York City (Offsite-box 8, Folder 7)
  - Offices, office furniture and equipment (pens, stationary, etc) (Offsite-box 9, Folder 1)
  - Piano and string instruments; Bells (Offsite-box 9, Folder 2)
  - Plumbing, baths and laundry (Offsite-box 9, Folder 3)
  - Printing specimens (Offsite-box 9, Folder 4)
  - Printing and publishing; book sellers and reading (Offsite-box 9, Folder 5)
  - Products used in 1900, pages 1-83 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 6)
  - Products used in 1900, pages 85-171 (Offsite-box 9, Folder 7)
  - Scientific instruments; State seals (Offsite-box 9, Folder 8)
  - Seeds and flowers (folder 1 of 2) (Offsite-box 9, Folder 9)
  - Seeds and flowers (folder 2 of 2) (Offsite-box 10, Folder 1)
  - Shoes and leather; Rubber goods (Offsite-box 10, Folder 2)
  - Silk and cotton (Offsite-box 10, Folder 3)
  - Store catalog, Army and Navy Cooperative, 1900 (Offsite-box 10, Folder 4)
  - Street cars; Streets and street scenes; servants (Offsite-box 10, Folder 5)
  - Tea; Tobacco; Confections (Offsite-box 10, Folder 6)
  - Toiletries and Perfume (Offsite-box 10, Folder 7)
  - Trees; Waterfalls (Offsite-box 10, Folder 8)
  - Undertakers and cemeteries; Vignettes of sickness; Crime and death (Offsite-box 10, Folder 9)
  - Vegetables and Fruits (Offsite-box 10, Folder 10)
  - Watches and Clocks (Offsite-box 10, Folder 11)
  - Wood Engravings, Index and sections 1-5 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 1)
  - Wood Engravings, Sections 6-9 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 2)
  - Wood Engravings, Sections 10-15 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 3)
  - Wood Engravings, Sections 16-20 (Offsite-box 11, Folder 4)
- Series II. Creative projects and research files
  This series includes Dorsey's proposal for a book on the Centennial Exhibition. Also included are several "concept" scrapbooks containing proposals for two theatrical musicals: "The Ballad of Josie and Jim", about the murder of robber baron Jim Fiske over actress Josie Mansfield, and "Centennial Quartette", a celebration of the 1876 Centennial Exhibition in Philadelphia. Dorsey also submitted the latter for consideration as a motion picture or television production, as is reflected by correspondence included in the series. None of these projects were realized.
  In addition, the series contains some of Dorsey's research files, consisting primarily of contemporaneous newspaper and magazine articles on the Bicentennial of 1976 and a few other topics (Antiques, Art Nouveau, the Metropolitan Opera House and Restaurants and Food). There are also a few folders of ephemera, primarily relating to architectural preservation and tourism in New York City in the 1960's and 1970's. Among the ephemera items are flyers for lectures on architectural preservation, brochures and maps for walking tours of New York City, brochures on churches and other historic buildings, and a 1905 Report of the Queens United Civic Association's Committee on City Plan and Parks. In the folder labeled "Assorted Ephemera" are tickets to the 1964 World's Fair, the 1974 Art Deco Exposition, and programs for two performances at Carnegie Hall (1898 and 1899) and a 1929 production of the Frieburg Passion Play at the New York Hippodrome.
  - The Ballad of Josie and Jim (folder 1 of 2) (Offsite-box 11, Folder 5)
  - The Ballad of Josie and Jim (folder 2 of 2) (Offsite-box 11, Folder 6)
  - "Centennial Quartette for the Musical of 1876" (folder 1 of 2) (Offsite-box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Centennial Quartette for the Musical of 1876" (folder 2 of 2) (Offsite-box 12, Folder 2)
  - "Centennial Quartette," manuscript and correspondence, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 3)
  - Centennial Exhibition Book Proposal- Notes (folder 1 of 2) (Offsite-box 12, Folder 4)
  - Centennial Exhibition Book Proposal- Notes (folder 2 of 2) (Offsite-box 12, Folder 5)
  - Centennial Exhibition Book Proposal- Notes and correspondence (Offsite-box 12, Folder 6)
  - Clippings & Musicals, 1972-1973 (Offsite-box 12, Folder 7)
  - Bicentennial Clippings, March 1967- December 1970 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 1)
  - Bicentennial Clippings, January - August 1971 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 2)
  - Bicentennial Clippings, September 1971 - February 1972 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 3)
  - Bicentennial Clippings, March - December 1972 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 4)
  - Bicentennial Clippings, January - December 1973 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 5)
  - Bicentennial Clippings, January 1974 - January 1975 (Offsite-box 13, Folder 6)
  - Antiques, 1965 - 1970 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 1)
  - Antiques, 1970 - 1975 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 2)
  - Art Nouveau, 1910-1913 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 3)
  - Art Nouveau, 1966 - 1974 (Offsite-box 14, Folder 4)
  - Art Nouveau, 1959, 1966, undated (ephemera) (Offsite-box 14, Folder 5)
  - Brighton (Offsite-box 14, Folder 6)
  - Metropolitan Opera House (Offsite-box 14, Folder 7)
  - Restaurants and food (Offsite-box 15, Folder 1)
  - Ephemera -- architectural preservation (Offsite-box 15, Folder 2)
  - Ephemera -- transportation and maps (Offsite-box 15, Folder 3)
  - Ephemera -- walking tours (Offsite-box 15, Folder 4)
  - Ephemera -- assorted (Offsite-box 15, Folder 5)
  - Sketches and source clippings (Offsite-box 15, Folder 6)
  - Americana Magazine (2 issues), 1976 July, 1978 June (Offsite-box 15, Folder 7)
  - Demorest's magazine (clippings), 1875-1889 (Offsite-box 68, Folder 1)
  - Life magazine mid-century issue, 1950 January 2 (Offsite-box 68, Folder 2)
- Series III. Scrapbooks
  Series III, Scrapbooks, contains an eclectic assortment of vintage illustrations and ephemera that Dorsey pasted into scrapbooks organized by topic. Materials include newspaper and magazine clippings, articles and other textual material, illustrations, photographs, postcards, greeting cards, advertisements, programs, and many other types of ephemera. Although the bulk of the materials are vintage, Dorsey also mixed in some contemporaneous (circa 1960's - 1970's) photographs and articles.
  Dorsey arranged these materials into elaborate topical scrapbooks that serve as interesting and creative reference files on a broad range of subjects. The largest segment of this series relates to New York City, covering topics such as Wall Street, the Fire Department, street cleaning, the poor and destitute, and many others which are specifically identified in the box and folder list, below. There are also scrapbooks relating to other American cities and states, especially the American West, and to European countries and other foreign locales. Other topics include dining, hotels and resorts (in New York and elsewhere), sports, ships, trains, houses, furnishings and people (including African Americans and other ethnic groups). There are a number of scrapbooks relating to fairs and expositions, including the Crystal Palace, Centennial Exposition, World's Columbian Exposition, Louisiana Purchase Exposition, and the Panama-Pacific International Exposition.
  The original binders were also created by Dorsey, and feature cardboard covers with sometimes elaborate lettering and decorations, bound together with three metal rings. The scrapbooks have been disbound and re-housed in acid-free folders. A few representative examples of the binders have been retained.
  - NYC -- Volume 9A: Equestrian, Clubs, Dogs, Entertainment, Theatre portraits (Offsite-box 19, Folder 1-2)
  - NYC -- Volume 10A: Destitute and poor, hospitals, prisons, 42nd Street, Bronx residences, Bowling Green, Broad Street, Broadway (street) (Offsite-box 20, Folder 1)
  - NYC-- Volume 11B, Sections 8-10: Lower Manhattan, Churches, Columbus Circle (Offsite-box 20, Folder 2)
  - NYC -- Volume 11B, Sections 11-13: Columbia College, City Hall, Courthouses, Criminals (Offsite-box 21, Folder 1)
  - NYC -- Volume 11B, Sections 14-15: East River Bridges, Ellis Island, Immigrants (Offsite-box 21, Folder 2)
  - NYC -- Volume 12C, Sections 16-17:Harbor Views (includes Customs, Docks, Statue of Liberty), Fifth Avenue, Institutions, Museums (Offsite-box 21, Folder 3)
  - NYC -- Volume 12C, Sections 18-20: Fire Department, Utilities, Medical (hospitals and colleges) (Offsite-box 22, Folder 1)
  - NYC -- Volume 12C, Sections 21-23: Maps, Horse shows, Madison Square Garden, Madison Avenue, NYC markets (Offsite-box 22, Folder 2)
  - NYC -- Volume 13D, Sections 24-25: Newspaper boys, Newspaper publishing companies, Coney Island, Water entertainment (Offsite-box 22, Folder 3)
  - NYC -- Volume 13D, Sections 26-30: Politics, Post offices, Playgrounds, the Poor, Riverside Drive, Audubon's House (Offsite-box 23, Folder 1)
  - NYC -- Volume 14E, Sections 31-32: Singer Tower, Suffragettes, Street scenes (Offsite-box 23, Folder 2)
  - NYC -- Volume 14E, Sections 33-34: Stores, Central Park (Offsite-box 23, Folder 3)
  - NYC -- Volume 15F, Sections 35-39: Wall Street, Stock Exchange, Woolworth Building, Snowstorms, Blizzards, Washington Square, Weather Bureau (Offsite-box 24, Folder 1)
  - NYC -- Volume 15F, Sections 40-43: Soldiers, Military, Sixth Avenue, Apartments, Hotels, 14th Street, Harlem River Bridge (Offsite-box 24, Folder 2)
  - NYC -- Volume 15F, Section 44: Political figures, Artists, Aristocrats (Offsite-box 24, Folder 3)
  - NYC -- Volume 15F, Sections 45-46: Aerial views of NYC, Brooklyn (Offsite-box 25, Folder 1)
  - NYC -- Volume 16G, Sections 47-49: Street Cleaners, 42nd Street, Railroads, Trolley Cars (Offsite-box 25, Folder 2)
  - NYC -- Volume 16G, Sections 49-50: Telephone Exchange, Advertising Cards, Calling Cards (Offsite-box 25, Folder 3)
  - NYC -- 23rd Street (Offsite-box 26, Folder 1-2)
  - NYC -- Crystal Palace (Offsite-box 26, Folder 3)
  - NYC -- Edwardian Theatre (Offsite-box 26, Folder 4-5)
  - NYC -- Theatre Programs (Offsite-box 27, Folder 1)
  - Sheet music and phonographs; English/French Food (Offsite-box 27, Folder 2)
  - Dining (pp. 1-30) (Offsite-box 28, Folder 1)
  - Dining (pp. 31-62) (Offsite-box 28, Folder 2)
  - Dining (pp. 63-80) (Offsite-box 28, Folder 3)
  - Dining (loose materials) (Offsite-box 28, Folder 4)
  - Dining (pp. 81-106) (Offsite-box 29, Folder 1)
  - Dining (pp. 107-134) (Offsite-box 29, Folder 2)
  - Dining (pp. 135-160) (Offsite-box 29, Folder 3)
  - Dining (pp. 161-176) (Offsite-box 30, Folder 1)
  - Dining (pp. 177-214) (Offsite-box 30, Folder 2)
  - Dining (pp. 215-241) (Offsite-box 30, Folder 3)
  - Drinking (folder 1 of 4) (Offsite-box 31, Folder 1-4)
  - Franco Prussian War 1870 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 1)
  - Paris 1870 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 2)
  - Paris 1876 (Offsite-box 32, Folder 3)
  - Paris -- Fin de Siecle (folder 1 of 4) (Offsite-box 33, Folder 1-4)
  - Paris Exposition (Offsite-box 34, Folder 1-2)
  - Crystal Palace London 1851 (Offsite-box 34, Folder 3)
  - Dore's London (Offsite-box 34, Folder 4)
  - European -- England (Offsite-box 35, Folder 1)
  - European -- Belgium, Denmark, Dutch, England (Offsite-box 35, Folder 2)
  - European -- France (Offsite-box 35, Folder 3)
  - European -- France (Offsite-box 36, Folder 1)
  - European -- Germany (Offsite-box 36, Folder 2)
  - European -- Greece, Hungary, India, Ireland (Offsite-box 36, Folder 3)
  - European -- Italy (Offsite-box 37, Folder 1)
  - European -- Italy; Latin America- Mexico (Offsite-box 37, Folder 2)
  - European -- Portugal, Spain, Miscellaneous (Offsite-box 38, Folder 1)
  - European -- Switzerland; Tunisia (Offsite-box 38, Folder 2)
  - Rural USA (Offsite-box 38, Folder 3)
  - Rural USA (Offsite-box 39, Folder 1)
  - Boston (Offsite-box 39, Folder 2-3)
  - Philadelphia (Offsite-box 40, Folder 1-2)
  - Old San Francisco (Offsite-box 40, Folder 3)
  - San Francisco Earthquake (Offsite-box 40, Folder 4)
  - USA West (Offsite-box 41, Folder 1-4)
  - USA West -- Arizona Highways magazine (5 issues - from USA West scrapbook), 1960 June, 1961 February, 1963 March-April, 1972 March (Offsite-box 15, Folder 8)
  - USA West -- Brochures for Grand Canyon and Monterey Bay; article on Charlie Russel, 1958, 1962, 1972, undated (Offsite-box 15, Folder 9)
  - Colorado (Offsite-box 16, Folder 1-6)
  - Colorado (Offsite-box 17, Folder 1-2)
  - Colorado -- Durango (Offsite-box 17, Folder 3)
  - Colorado -- Hotel Broadmoor (Offsite-box 17, Folder 4)
  - Colorado -- Hotel de Paris (Offsite-box 17, Folder 5)
  - US Cities -- California to Kentucky (Offsite-box 42, Folder 1-3)
  - US Cities -- Louisiana to Wisconsin (Offsite-box 43, Folder 1-3)
  - World's Columbian Exposition, Chicago, Illinois, 1893 (Offsite-box 43, Folder 4)
  - World's Columbian Exposition, Chicago, Illinois, 1893 (Offsite-box 44, Folder 1-3)
  - World's Columbian Exposition, Illustrated (Offsite-box 44, Folder 4)
  - World's Columbian Exposition, Illustrated (Offsite-box 45, Folder 1-4)
  - World's Columbian Exposition -- articles (Offsite-box 17, Folder 7-8)
  - Louisiana Purchase: Exposition St Louis, MO, 1904 (folder 1 of 2) (Offsite-box 46, Folder 1-2)
  - Miscellaneous centennials and fairs (Offsite-box 46, Folder 3)
  - Panama-Pacific International Exposition, 1915, San Francisco (Offsite-box 46, Folder 4)
  - The Centennial 1876 (Offsite-box 47, Folder 1-4)
  - The Centennial 1876 (Offsite-box 48, Folder 1-5)
  - US Hotels and Resorts (Offsite-box 49, Folder 1-3)
  - US Hotels and Resorts -- Alabama to Missouri (folder 1 of 3) (Offsite-box 50, Folder 1-3)
  - US Hotels and Resorts -- Nevada to Wisconsin (Offsite-box 51, Folder 1-2)